Matthew J. Finnell

(425) 351-2896 Mattfinnell104@gmail.com www.mattfinnell.io

Profile

Software Development Engineer with 3 years experience. I studied Computer Science at Western Washington University and am currently searching for a position as a Developer in the Seattle Area. My strengths include the ability to create dynamic websites using multiple frameworks, rapidly tailor front end code, and manage data from many sources.

Experience

SPIE - Full Stack Software Engineering Intern

June 2015 - June 2016

I contributed to upgrading portions of website infrastructure from .NET V2.0 to .NET MVC V4.0. This required that I revamp many aspx webforms to take on a new graphical front end, be MVC compliant, and communicate between existing SQL databases and Sharepoint.

Technology Alliance Group NW - Volunteer Developer

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015

I helped design a backend system that would pull in JSON and XML data from multiple APIs and perform data checks to ensure that data is consistent between each API. This was implemented with a Python backend that communicated with RESTful WebServices and a variety of databases.

Prepared Response - Front End Web Development Intern

June 2014 - Jan 2015

Collaborated with both graphic designers and developers to redesign the corporate website. I successfully reimplemented the new site using HTML5, twitter bootstrap, javascript, jQuery and AJAX. The resulting website was more dynamic, responsive and leaner than the previous website.

Education

Bellevue Senior High School Western Washington University (Computer Science)

Skills

Software Development using C#, Python and Java Web Development using HTML, CSS, Javascript Database Management using T-SQL, mySQL, and mongoDB Web Service Interaction using RESTful APIs and Sharepoint Version Control using Git and TFS